# **AHMED MOHAMED**

Al Madinah Province | (C) +966556686566 | ahmed.hitec@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ahmedmohameddevloper/

# **Professional Summary**

Oracle Developer with over 10 years providing technical solutions through high-quality service and support. Seeking position in a challenging and rewarding tech environment where I can expand upon my existing skill base while contributing to a lively IT team.

# **Skills**

- Troubleshooting and debugging
- SQL specialist
- PL-SQL specialist
- Oracle Forms specialist
- Oracle Reports specialist
- Java specialist
- ADF specialist

- Interpersonal skills
- Working with shifting priorities
- Web application development
- Managing multiple projects simultaneously
- E-commerce background
- Advanced problem solving skills

# **Work History**

Oracle / Java Developer EBTTIKAR Technology Co – Saudi Arabia

**Operation and maintenance project** 

- \* Gathering and documenting customer requirements
- \* Developing Oracle forms and Reports as per customer requirements
- \* Applying ITIL standards and requirements
- \* Integrating Oracle Application with GIS services
- \* Developing custom archive system using java beans and oracle forms
- \* Implementing solutions for the core businesses building licences, Naming
  - & Numbering, Space & Layout Implementation and Urban Planning
- \* Implementing ADF system as a replacement of forms 10g in some modules.

**Oracle Developer** 

01/2011 to 03/2012

06/2012 to Current

Omar Kassem Alesayi Group OKAG – Saudi Arabya

## **Migration Project at Madinah Municipality**

- \* Developing java based tool to migrate forms and reports from 6i to 10g
- \* Configuring Oracle Application Server 10g for production environment
- \* Developing database scripts to migrate and restructure database schema.
- \* Developing database procedures and function to support the migration process
- \* Useing web-util to integrate with client-side application
- \* Applying Multi-Organization model for Madinah sub-municipalities

**Oracle Developer** 01/2010 to 01/2011

#### Networks Valley – Egypt

- \* implementing custom ERP product at (Cairo-Eclectic-Production-Company)
- \* implementing custom ERP product at (New & Renewable Energy Authority )
- \* Support of custom ERP in two sites.
- \* Join migration project from Oracle forms 6i to Oracle forms 10g in Madinah Municipality

**Content Developer** 01/2009 to 01/2010

## Helwan University e-learning center - Egypt

- \* Develop learning courses content using HTML and / or JavaScript
- \* Administer open source course management system ( moodle )
- \* Upgrade ,customize and maintain moodle
- \* Develop web-application (ASP.NET) to manage the business process in the center

## **Education**

Bachelor of Science: 2007

# **Management Information System -**

## General studies in the following fields

- \* Accounting
- \* Management
- \* Economics

#### Specialized Studies in the following fields

- \* Computer networking
- \* Operating Systems
- \* Programming and Data Structure
- \* Database Structure
- \* Information Technology Security
- \*System analysis and design

# **Certifications and Training**

#### **Certification:**

- \* OCP Oracle database 10g administration
- \* OCP Oracle forms and reports developer

## **Training at Oracle University**

- \* Oracle Linux
- \* Managing Oracle over Linux
- \* Oracle discoverer end user
- \* Oracle database 10g Advanced PLSQL
- \* Networking and Security